<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Last news</title>
    <link>http://localhost/edu/php3/news/news.php</link>
    <item>
      <title>A.I. Can Now Create Lifelike Videos. Can You Tell What’s Real?</title>
      <link>nytimes.com</link>
      <description><![CDATA[Artificial intelligence tools can create picture-perfect faces, realistic photographs and now lifelike videos.

While A.I. video technology is not yet as sophisticated as tools that create images and audio, it is rapidly advancing. The most convincing examples often manipulate real videos, adding realistic A.I. elements.]]></description>
      <pubDate>1725893266</pubDate>
      <category>Culture</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What Harris and Trump Say About Each Other</title>
      <link>nytimes.com</link>
      <description><![CDATA[In an unprecedented moment in modern American history, the 2024 Republican and Democratic presidential candidates will face off in their first debate after just seven weeks of campaigning against each other.

The New York Times analyzed what the two candidates have said about each other on social media from July 21, when President Biden dropped out of the race and Vice President Kamala Harris became the frontrunner to replace him as the Democratic nominee, through Sept. 6. (For the most part, their statements on social media mirror their public comments at rallies and other events.)

While both candidates attack each other, The Times found that former president Donald Trump targets Ms. Harris much more frequently, an average of more than three times per day, and his posts (on Truth Social) almost always include a personal smear.]]></description>
      <pubDate>1725892131</pubDate>
      <category>Politics</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ronaldo reaches 900 career goals - the numbers behind the landmark</title>
      <link>bbc.com</link>
      <description><![CDATA[Cristiano Ronaldo reached a significant milestone on Thursday by scoring the 900th goal of his illustrious career.

The 39-year-old struck for Portugal in their Nations League game against Croatia, putting them 2-0 up.

It prompted an emotional celebration by the forward, as he dropped to his knees by the corner flag in tears.

The goal was his 131st for his country, while he has also scored at club level for Sporting Lisbon, Manchester United, Real Madrid, Juventus and current club Al-Nassr.

"It was emotional because it's a milestone," Ronaldo said. "It seems like any other milestone but only I know, and the people around me, how hard it is to work every day, to be physically and psychologically fit, to score 900 goals.

"It's a unique milestone in my career."]]></description>
      <pubDate>1725629007</pubDate>
      <category>Sports</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Harris’ liberal record is hiding in plain sight</title>
      <link>washingtontimes.com</link>
      <description><![CDATA[Vice President Kamala Harris is battling to win moderate swing-state voters by burying her liberal record in the Senate.

Ms. Harris served four years as the junior senator from California, establishing one of the most liberal voting records among all Democrats, including self-declared democratic socialist Sen. Bernard Sanders of Vermont.

When she became vice president in 2021, her liberal voting streak continued. She cast the Senate’s tiebreaking vote a record 33 times to confirm some of the most liberal executive branch appointees and federal judges and to pass nearly $2 trillion in federal spending that many economists blame for driving inflation to near 40-year highs.]]></description>
      <pubDate>1725628462</pubDate>
      <category>Politics</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>WWI memorial completed with 25-ton sculpture honoring the American doughboy</title>
      <link>washingtontimes.com</link>
      <description><![CDATA[No American doughboys remain alive to recall wading through the trenches of the Great War more than a century ago, so a new sculpture in the nation’s capital seeks to speak for them.

Officials recently announced that the National World War I Memorial will reach its completion with the unveiling of a 25-ton bronze sculpture honoring the typical U.S. infantryman — nicknamed “doughboy” for the flour used to polish their white belts — who fought in the last months of the global conflict that ended in 1918. 

The 60-foot-long sculpture, “A Soldier’s Journey,” evokes the epic myth of the hero’s journey and will be the largest of its kind in the northern hemisphere. Officials plan to illuminate it during a nighttime ceremony on Sept. 13, the 164th birthday of Gen. John J. Pershing, who led the American Expeditionary Forces in Europe from 1917 to 1920.]]></description>
      <pubDate>1725626190</pubDate>
      <category>Culture</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What Do Progressive Parents Owe Their Public Schools?</title>
      <link>newyorker.com</link>
      <description><![CDATA[In August, the Oakland Unified School District (O.U.S.D.) informed parents that children at more than twenty of the system’s campuses had been exposed to harmful levels of lead in their drinking water. At Lincoln Elementary in the city’s Chinatown neighborhood, tests showed levels as high as nine hundred and thirty parts per billion in the drinking water, or sixty-two times the state and federal government’s threshold of fifteen parts per billion. Crocker Highlands Elementary and HillCrest Elementary, widely regarded as two of the best and wealthiest schools in the district, had as high as four hundred and forty parts per billion and a hundred p.p.b., respectively. The scandal has cut across racial and class lines. Roughly two-thirds of O.U.S.D.’s students are either Black or Latino, but the four campuses with the highest contamination levels have disproportionately large white and Asian enrollments.]]></description>
      <pubDate>1725625626</pubDate>
      <category>Culture</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How Latin America’s largest country is falling for football</title>
      <link>washingtonpost.com</link>
      <description><![CDATA[RIO DE JANEIRO — Sitting at home in this sun-soaked Brazilian metropolis, Flavia Ponce de Leon was daydreaming again of that distant, magical place.

Green Bay, Wis.

She said she can envision it all: The wide roads. The frigid winters. And, most importantly, her cherished Green Bay Packers.

“The Packers are my family,” she says. “My heart is in Wisconsin.”

Ponce de Leon — who has covered the walls of her living room in green and gold Packers gear, tattooed the team’s G logo on her arm and named her cat for former linebacker Clay Matthews — is far from the traditional Cheesehead. She doesn’t speak any English. She has no history in Wisconsin. And she was born, raised and lives in Brazil, the nation that gave the world Pelé and his Beautiful Game, that has won five World Cup soccer titles, where families welcome newborns with infant-sized soccer jerseys and the only football most anyone has ever loved is futebol.

But now, Latin America’s largest country is falling for another football — the American variety — and, in the process, reorienting its longtime sports identity.]]></description>
      <pubDate>1725623301</pubDate>
      <category>Sports</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A tax on tourism</title>
      <link>washingtonpost.com</link>
      <description><![CDATA[WELLINGTON, New Zealand — Tourist taxes are increasingly being deployed by authorities around the world as a way to tackle “overtourism.”

New Zealand this week announced it is nearly tripling its visitor fee, introduced in 2019 to help protect the country’s natural beauty. Iceland reinstated its tourist tax this year after a brief pandemic suspension — raising the levy and expanding it to cruise ship operators — to fund conservation efforts.]]></description>
      <pubDate>1725622023</pubDate>
      <category>Culture</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>War within a war: Israel takes aim at Hamas militants in Lebanon</title>
      <link>washingtonpost.com</link>
      <description><![CDATA[SIDON, Lebanon — Hamas operative Nidal Hleihel was sitting in his car last month outside an apartment block in this Lebanese port city when he heard a loud crack above him. Spooked, he said, he scrambled out of the vehicle. He had just reached a nearby stairwell when the Israeli missile struck.

His sport utility vehicle went up in flames as a crowd began to gather. Hleihel, cut deeply by shrapnel but still alive, was rushed from the scene.

The attack was part of an intensifying Israeli assassination campaign against Palestinian militants in Lebanon — a war within a war that has been largely obscured by escalating exchanges of fire between the Israel Defense Forces and Hezbollah. Most of the Palestinians targeted are mid-level members of Hamas, involved in finance or logistics, but a January strike in Beirut’s southern suburbs killed Saleh Arouri, a senior political figure who helped found the group’s military wing.

“All Palestinian factions in Lebanon should be aware that at any moment, anyone could be assassinated,” Ayman Shanaa, Hamas’s deputy political chief in Lebanon, told The Washington Post.]]></description>
      <pubDate>1725617826</pubDate>
      <category>Politics</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dirty rooms, no mixed drinks: Inside a Boston hotel on strike</title>
      <link>washingtonpost.com</link>
      <description><![CDATA[Check-ins were delayed and towels were piled up at a Boston Hilton as Unite Here workers picketed on Labor Day.]]></description>
      <pubDate>1725616191</pubDate>
      <category>Culture</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>They call it ‘murderball.’ Wheelchair rugby isn’t for the faint of heart.</title>
      <link>washingtonpost.com</link>
      <description><![CDATA[At a Paralympic training camp, Chuck Aoki sped down the court in his wheelchair before getting rammed from the side by another player, which caused him to go tumbling, flipping three times in his chair before thudding onto the ground.

Aoki was unfazed. Crashes are to be expected in wheelchair rugby, a fast-paced, high-contact sport that challenges common stereotypes that view people in wheelchairs as fragile.

The sport was invented in the late 1970s by quadriplegics who wanted an alternative to wheelchair basketball but has grown increasingly popular over the past decade, thanks in part to faster, lighter wheelchairs and rule changes that have intensified the game.

One sign of the fiercer competition? The United States, which once dominated the sport, has not won a Paralympic gold medal in wheelchair rugby since 2008. As the matches begin today, the team will be looking to reclaim the top spot in the sport in Paris, but to do so, it will need to beat out seven other teams that are equally tough.]]></description>
      <pubDate>1725615453</pubDate>
      <category>Sports</category>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
